<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Recent posts by Nathan Baker</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</link><description>Recent posts by Nathan Baker</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 04:31:42 -0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/profile/feed.rss" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><item><title>PDB2PQR 2.0 release</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2014/12/pdb2pqr-20-release/</link><description>&lt;div class="markdown_content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear APBS and PDB2PQR users –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the release of PDB2PQR 2.0 which is now available from &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/docs/downloads/." rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/docs/downloads/.&lt;/a&gt;  There are several improvements and fixes (outlined below) to this release of the software and we encourage all users to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/release-history" rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/release-history&lt;/a&gt; for the complete release notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your continued support of APBS and PDB2PQR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The APBS/PDB2PQR development team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="pdb2pqr-200"&gt;PDB2PQR 2.0.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/release-history" rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/release-history&lt;/a&gt; for the complete release history&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="notable-new-features"&gt;Notable new features:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PDB2PKA as an alternative to PROPKA for calculating pH values used to protonate residues. This feature is EXPERIMENTAL. The libraries to make this feature available are included in the binary releases. They are NOT included in the source code and are not compiled with the rest of PDB2PQR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="new-features"&gt;NEW FEATURES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved look of web interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to automatically drop water from pdb file before processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of PDB2PKA into PDB2PQR as an alternative to PROPKA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for compiling with VS2008 in Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to build with debug headers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA now detects and reports non Henderson-Hasselbalch behavior. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA can be instructed whether or not to start from scratch with --pdb2pka-resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can now specify output directory for PDB2PKA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error regarding backbone in some cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed time format on querystatus page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error catching on web interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes"&gt;BUG FIXES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed executable name when creating binaries for Unix based operating systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed potential crash when using --clean with extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed MAXATOMS display on server home page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA now mostly respects the --verbose setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed how hydrogens are added by PDB2PKA for state changes in some cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed psize error check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will now build properly without ligand support if numpy is not installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed old automake build files from all tests ported to scons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed broken opal backend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="changes"&gt;CHANGES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command line interface to PROPKA changed to accommodate PDB2PKA. PROPKA is now used with --ph-calc-method=propka. --with-ph now defaults to 7.0 and is only required if a different pH value is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;--ph-calc-method to select optional method to calculate pH values used to protonate titratable residues. Possible options are "propka" and "pdb2pka". &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropped support for compilation with mingw. Building on Windows now requires VS 2008 installed in the default location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated included Scons to 2.3.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA can now be run directly (not integrated in PDB2PQR) with pka.py. Arguments are &amp;lt;PDB file=""&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;Output directory=""&amp;gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer providing 32-bit binary builds. PDB2PKA support is too memory intensive to make this practical in many cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="known-bugs"&gt;KNOWN BUGS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If more than one extension is run from the command line and one of the extensions modifies the protein data structure it could affect the output of the other extension. The only included extensions that exhibit this problem are resinter and newresinter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running ligands and PDB2PKA at the same time is not currently supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA currently leaks memory slowly. Small jobs will use about twice the normally required RAM (ie ~14 titratable residues will use 140MB). Big jobs will use about 5 times the normally required RAM ( 60 titratable residues will use 480MB ). We are working to fix this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 04:31:42 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.netc105002a2e1604a232ad553fc072fde196567b12</guid></item><item><title>APBS 1.4.1 released</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2014/08/apbs-141-released/</link><description>&lt;div class="markdown_content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear APBS users --&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the release of APBS 1.4.1. This was primarily a bug fix release, however, we have added a few new features we'd like to highlight:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Multigrid bug fix for volumes with large problem domains&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; We have added a preliminary implementation of geometric flow&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Finite element method support has been re-enabled&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; Migration of the APBS source tree to GitHub (https://github.com/Electrostatics/apbs-pdb2pqr) for better collaboration, issue tracking, and source code management&lt;br /&gt;
* Improved test suite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new version of APBS can be downloaded from &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/docs/downloads/#downloads." rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/docs/downloads/#downloads.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would also like to highlight our new web site, still located at: &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/." rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/.&lt;/a&gt; This site is also hosted at GitHub and we hope that the new organization will make it easier for people to find the content they need. While we are still in the process of migrating some remaining content, we have added links to the previous web page when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your continuing support of APBS. As always, please use our mailing lists to send us questions or comments about our software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The APBS Development Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 03:21:37 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net2cb8bab8cf5807e9fd095c14b8ffa3c20ca7a230</guid></item><item><title>Home modified by Nathan Baker</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/vwo/wiki/Home/</link><description>&lt;div class="markdown_content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your wiki!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the default page, edit it as you see fit. To add a new page simply reference it within brackets, e.g.: &lt;span&gt;[SamplePage]&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wiki uses &lt;a class="" href="/p/vwo/wiki/markdown_syntax/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;Project Members:&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;ul class="md-users-list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/u/anadikumar/"&gt;Anadi Kumar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/u/sobolevnrm/"&gt;Nathan Baker&lt;/a&gt; (admin)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/u/samthakur74/"&gt;samthakur74&lt;/a&gt; (admin)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/u/superpesto/"&gt;superpesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="download-button-5178107ce88f3d0a8f5da4aa" style="margin-bottom: 1em; display: block;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 17:03:59 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net69781348acaabc926c15704bd7d55b6dbaba614d</guid></item><item><title>WikiPage Home modified by Nathan Baker</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/wiki/Home/</link><description>Welcome to your wiki!

This is the default page, edit it as you see fit. To add a new page simply reference it within brackets, e.g.: [SamplePage].

The wiki uses [Markdown](/p/pdb2pqr/wiki/markdown_syntax/) syntax.

[[project_admins]]
[[download_button]]
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 17:40:35 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net4fcb7cc9298cac27331a0d3c7bdb05690bf26e79</guid></item><item><title>WikiPage Home modified by Nathan Baker</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/wiki/Home/</link><description>Welcome to your wiki!

This is the default page, edit it as you see fit. To add a new page simply reference it within brackets, e.g.: [SamplePage].

The wiki uses [Markdown](/p/apbs/wiki/markdown_syntax/) syntax.

[[project_admins]]
[[download_button]]
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 17:40:24 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net7c548b18b1b509c6cbc3a6ebf02446136ec408d8</guid></item><item><title>APBS 1.4.0 released</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2012/08/apbs-140-released/</link><description>Dear APBS users --

We are pleased to announce the release of APBS 1.4.0.  This version of APBS includes a massive rewrite to eliminate FORTRAN from the software code base to improve portability and facilitate planned optimization and parallelization activities.  A more detailed list of changes is provided below.

Starting with this release, we have created separate installation packages for the APBS binaries, examples, and programmer's documentation.  This change is in response to user requests and recognition of the large size of the examples and documentation directories.

As usual, APBS can be freely downloaded from http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/apbs/downloads.

Thank you for your continued support of APBS.

Sincerely,

The APBS Development Team

\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#
Please see http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/apbs/release-history for the complete change log

\# These are notes for the current version of APBS
\* Removed FORTRAN dependency from APBS
\- Direct line by line translation of all source from contrib/pmgZ
\- Functions replaced and tested incrementally to ensure code congruence
\- Created new subfolder src/pmgC for translated pmg library
\- Created new macros for 2d, 3d matrix access
&amp;gt; In src/generic/apbs/vmatrix.h
&amp;gt; Simulate native FORTRAN 2 and 3 dimensional arrays
&amp;gt; Use 1-indexed, column-major ordering
&amp;gt; Allowed direct 1-1 translation from FORTRAN to ensurre code congruence
\* Added additional debugging and output macros to src/generic/apbs/vhal.h
\- Added message, error message, assertion, warning, and abort macros
\- Macro behavior modified by the --enable-debug flag for configure
&amp;gt; Non-error messages directed to stderr in debug, io.mc otherwise
&amp;gt; All error messages are directed to stdout
&amp;gt; In debug mode, verbose location information is provided
\* Added additional flags to configure
\- --with-fetk replaces FETK\_INCLUDE, FETK\_LIBRARY environment flags
\- --with-efence enables compiling with electric fence library
\- --enable-debug eliminates compiling optimization and includes line no info
\- --enable-profiling adds profiling information and sets --enable-debug
\- --enable-verbose-debug prints lots of function specific information

\# REMOVED CODE
\* contrib/pmgZ has been removed
\* contrib/blas has been removed
\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#

</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 14:20:48 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net39b80b148ba791f35b765ace78e97057c8edfd51</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR 1.8 released</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2012/01/pdb2pqr-18-released/</link><description>We are pleased to announce the release of PBD2PQR 1.8.  This version includes support for the new PROPKA 3.0 pKa software, several improvements to the command line extensions functionality, as well as improvements to the PDB2PQR web server.  A full list of changes is available in the release history page.

As usual, PDB2PQR can be run through the web or downloaded for use on your computer.  Access to both the web server and the downloadable software is available at http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/d.

Thank you for your continuing support of PDB2PQR.

Sincerely,

The PDB2PQR Development Team</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 13:08:31 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net909937daaa3ff88ba657c2d96020daaac9953843</guid></item><item><title>New APBS Windows Installer</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2012/01/new-apbs-windows-installer/</link><description>We have released a new version of the APBS Windows Installer with the following features:

\* Ability to customize install path with correct behavior
\* Interactive command line interface when double-clicking APBS program

Please let us know if you have any questions or concerns about this new installer.

Thank you for your support of APBS.
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 16:22:35 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net8e2845a06686f838bee394e5f14ba630432c366c</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR 1.7.1</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2011/08/pdb2pqr-171/</link><description>Dear PDB2PQR users --

We are pleased to announce the release of PDB2PQR 1.7.1.  This release contains several new features and bug fixes which are described in detail at http://goo.gl/w0BxD. Among these changes are several important features which should be of broad interest to the community. 

The primary URL for APBS Opal support has changed to leverage services provided by the National Biomedical Computation Resource \(http://nbcr.net/\).  This provides additional computational resources to users who are interested in running calculations on remote resources.
Added more JMol controls for visualization.
Improved error reporting.
Fixed many bugs in both the command line and web version.
Improved behavior of –userff and –usernames command line switches for user created force fields. –usernames now works properly. See http://goo.gl/pXNNZ
The new version of PDB2PQR can be downloaded from http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/d

Thank you for your continuing support of PDB2PQR.

Sincerely,

The PDB2PQR Development Team</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 02:30:17 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net6833f4d668b090dd05e6e28d59013ad695cbd259</guid></item><item><title>APBS 1.3 released</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2010/10/apbs-13-released/</link><description>Dear APBS users --

We are pleased to announce the release of APBS 1.3.  This release contains several new features and bug fixes which are described in detail at http://goo.gl/l0Pt.  Among these changes are several important features which should be of broad interest to the community.

\* The primary URL for APBS Opal support has changed to leverage services provided by the National Biomedical Computation Resource \(http://nbcr.net/\).  This provides additional computational resources to users who are interested in running calculations on remote resources, as described at http://goo.gl/CHZy. 

\* APBS now supports the ability to write out atom-specific potentials using the "write atompot" keyword in the APBS input file.  This has been an often-requested feature and is described in more detail at http://goo.gl/iEAO.

\* APBS now supports the ability to read and write compressed \(GZIPped\) potential file output using the "write pot gz ..." command \(see http://goo.gl/iEAO\).

\* APBS now provides additional control over the numerical accuracy of the underlying calculations, giving users the opportunity to increase/decrease accuracy to change the speed of their calculations.

The new version of APBS can be downloaded from http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/apbs/downloads.

Thank you for your continuing support of APBS.

Sincerely,

The APBS Development Team
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 14:56:28 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net1d90eba3deedb27c4a1fad2cb2e6e67e5ab1624f</guid></item></channel></rss>