<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Recent changes to news</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/</link><description>Recent changes to news</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 04:31:42 -0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/feed.rss" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><item><title>PDB2PQR 2.0 release</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2014/12/pdb2pqr-20-release/</link><description>&lt;div class="markdown_content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear APBS and PDB2PQR users –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the release of PDB2PQR 2.0 which is now available from &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/docs/downloads/." rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/docs/downloads/.&lt;/a&gt;  There are several improvements and fixes (outlined below) to this release of the software and we encourage all users to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/release-history" rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/release-history&lt;/a&gt; for the complete release notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your continued support of APBS and PDB2PQR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The APBS/PDB2PQR development team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="pdb2pqr-200"&gt;PDB2PQR 2.0.0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/release-history" rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/release-history&lt;/a&gt; for the complete release history&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="notable-new-features"&gt;Notable new features:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PDB2PKA as an alternative to PROPKA for calculating pH values used to protonate residues. This feature is EXPERIMENTAL. The libraries to make this feature available are included in the binary releases. They are NOT included in the source code and are not compiled with the rest of PDB2PQR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="new-features"&gt;NEW FEATURES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved look of web interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to automatically drop water from pdb file before processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of PDB2PKA into PDB2PQR as an alternative to PROPKA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for compiling with VS2008 in Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to build with debug headers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA now detects and reports non Henderson-Hasselbalch behavior. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA can be instructed whether or not to start from scratch with --pdb2pka-resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can now specify output directory for PDB2PKA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error regarding backbone in some cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed time format on querystatus page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved error catching on web interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes"&gt;BUG FIXES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed executable name when creating binaries for Unix based operating systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed potential crash when using --clean with extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed MAXATOMS display on server home page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA now mostly respects the --verbose setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed how hydrogens are added by PDB2PKA for state changes in some cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed psize error check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will now build properly without ligand support if numpy is not installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed old automake build files from all tests ported to scons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed broken opal backend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="changes"&gt;CHANGES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command line interface to PROPKA changed to accommodate PDB2PKA. PROPKA is now used with --ph-calc-method=propka. --with-ph now defaults to 7.0 and is only required if a different pH value is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;--ph-calc-method to select optional method to calculate pH values used to protonate titratable residues. Possible options are "propka" and "pdb2pka". &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropped support for compilation with mingw. Building on Windows now requires VS 2008 installed in the default location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated included Scons to 2.3.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA can now be run directly (not integrated in PDB2PQR) with pka.py. Arguments are &amp;lt;PDB file=""&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;Output directory=""&amp;gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No longer providing 32-bit binary builds. PDB2PKA support is too memory intensive to make this practical in many cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="known-bugs"&gt;KNOWN BUGS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If more than one extension is run from the command line and one of the extensions modifies the protein data structure it could affect the output of the other extension. The only included extensions that exhibit this problem are resinter and newresinter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running ligands and PDB2PKA at the same time is not currently supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDB2PKA currently leaks memory slowly. Small jobs will use about twice the normally required RAM (ie ~14 titratable residues will use 140MB). Big jobs will use about 5 times the normally required RAM ( 60 titratable residues will use 480MB ). We are working to fix this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 04:31:42 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.netc105002a2e1604a232ad553fc072fde196567b12</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR 1.8 released</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2012/01/pdb2pqr-18-released/</link><description>We are pleased to announce the release of PBD2PQR 1.8.  This version includes support for the new PROPKA 3.0 pKa software, several improvements to the command line extensions functionality, as well as improvements to the PDB2PQR web server.  A full list of changes is available in the release history page.

As usual, PDB2PQR can be run through the web or downloaded for use on your computer.  Access to both the web server and the downloadable software is available at http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/d.

Thank you for your continuing support of PDB2PQR.

Sincerely,

The PDB2PQR Development Team</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 13:08:31 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net909937daaa3ff88ba657c2d96020daaac9953843</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR 1.7.1</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2011/08/pdb2pqr-171/</link><description>Dear PDB2PQR users --

We are pleased to announce the release of PDB2PQR 1.7.1.  This release contains several new features and bug fixes which are described in detail at http://goo.gl/w0BxD. Among these changes are several important features which should be of broad interest to the community. 

The primary URL for APBS Opal support has changed to leverage services provided by the National Biomedical Computation Resource \(http://nbcr.net/\).  This provides additional computational resources to users who are interested in running calculations on remote resources.
Added more JMol controls for visualization.
Improved error reporting.
Fixed many bugs in both the command line and web version.
Improved behavior of –userff and –usernames command line switches for user created force fields. –usernames now works properly. See http://goo.gl/pXNNZ
The new version of PDB2PQR can be downloaded from http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/d

Thank you for your continuing support of PDB2PQR.

Sincerely,

The PDB2PQR Development Team</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 02:30:17 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net6833f4d668b090dd05e6e28d59013ad695cbd259</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR 1.7 released</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2010/10/pdb2pqr-17-released/</link><description>Dear APBS and PDB2PQR users --

I am happy to announce the release of PDB2PQR 1.7 which includes two major updates:

\* For PDB2PQR web interface users:  the JMol web interface for APBS calculation visualization has been substantially improved, thanks to help from Bob Hanson.  Those performing APBS calculations via the PDB2PQR web interface now have a much wider range of options for visualizing the output online -- as well as downloading for offline analysis.

\* For PDB2PQR command-line and custom web interface users:  the Opal service URLs have changed to new NBCR addresses.  Old services hosted at \*.wustl.edu addresses have been decommissioned.  Please upgrade ASAP to use the new web service.  Thank you as always to the staff at NBCR for their continuing support of APBS/PDB2PQR web servers and services.

You can learn more about the latest version of PDB2PQR at http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr.  Access to the web interface and to downloads can be found at http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr/d.  

Thank you for your continuing support of PDB2PQR.

Sincerely,

The PDB2PQR Development Team
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 16:40:01 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net4b12ca4b2de29b012e1cce2e416ea8b9b44cb4b1</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR 1.6 released</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2010/04/pdb2pqr-16-released/</link><description>Dear PDB2PQR users --

We are pleased to announce the release of PDB2PQR 1.6.  This version has several new features as well minor fixes to reported bugs.  A complete list of changes is provided below.  For more information about the new release, to download binaries, or access the PDB2PQR web servers, please visit http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/pdb2pqr

Thank you for your continuing support of the PDB2PQR software.

Sincerely,

Nathan Baker


\- NEW FEATURES
\* Added Swanson force field based on Swanson et al paper \(http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ct600216k\).
\* Modified printAtoms\(\) method. Now &amp;quot;TER&amp;quot; is printed at the end of every chain.
\* Added Google Analytics code to get the statistics on the production server.
\* Modified APBS calculation page layout to hide parameters by default and display PDB ID
\* Added &amp;quot;make test-webserver&amp;quot;, which tests a long list of PDBs \(246 PDBs\) on the production PDB2PQR web server.
\* Removed nlev from inputgen.py and inputgen\_pKa.py as nlev keyword is now deprecated in APBS.
\* Added PARSE parameters for RNA, data from: Tang C. L., Alexov E, Pyle A. M., Honig B. Calculation of pKas in RNA: On the Structural Origins and Functional Roles of Protonated Nucleotides. Journal of Molecular Biology 366 \(5\) 1475-1496, 2007.


\- BUG FIXES
\* Fixed a minor bug: when starting pka.py from pdb2pka directory using command like &amp;quot;python pka.py \[options\] inputfile&amp;quot;, we need to make sure scriptpath does not end with &amp;quot;/&amp;quot;.
\* Fixed a bug which caused &amp;quot;coercing to Unicode: need string or buffer, instance found&amp;quot; when submitting PDB2PQR jobs with user-defined force fields on Opal based web server. 
\* Fixed a bug in main\_cgi.py, now Opal-based PDB2PQR jobs should also be logged in usage.txt file.
\* Updated src/utilities.py with a bug fix provided by Greg Cipriano, which prevents infinite loops in analyzing connected atoms in certain cases.
\* Fixed a bug related to neutraln and/or neutralc selections on the web server.
\* Fixed a special case with --ffout and 1AIK, where the N-terminus is acetylated.
\* Fixed a bug in psize.py per Michael Lerner's suggestion. The old version of psize.py gives wrong cglen and fglen results in special cases \(e.g., all y coordinates are negative values\).
\* Fixed a bug in main\_cgi.py, eliminated input/output file name confusions whether a PDB ID or a pdb file is provided on the web server.
\* Fixed a bug which causes run time error on the web server when user-defined force field and names files are provided.
\* Fixed a bug in apbs\_cgi.py: pdb file names submitted by users are not always 4 characters long.</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 21:29:26 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.netbaf38da060314b12868eb1108403fdfbc0cfd8ab</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR 1.4.0 released</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2009/04/pdb2pqr-140-released/</link><description>Dear PDB2PQR users -- 

We are pleased to announce the release of PDB2PQR version 1.4.0, which contains a number of new features including integration of PDB2PQR and APBS Opal services through remote clusters at NBCR. A complete list of new features and bug fixes is provided below.  

As usual, PDB2PQR can be downloaded from http://pdb2pqr.sourceforge.net/ and help can be obtained from the PDB2PQR-users mailing list \(subscribe: https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/pdb2pqr-users or browse: https://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/forum.php?forum\_name=pdb2pqr-users\).

Thank you for your continuing support of PDB2PQR. 

Sincerely, 

The PDB2PQR Development Team

\- NEW FEATURES
\* Updated html/master-index.html, deleted html/index.php.
\* Updated pydoc by running genpydoc.sh.
\* Added a whitespace option by by putting whitespaces between atom name
and residue name, between x and y, and between y and z.
\* Added radius for Chlorine in ligff.py.
\* Added PEOEPB forcefield, data provided by Paul Czodrowski.
\* Updated inputgen.py to write out the electrostatic potential for APBS
input file. 
\* Updated CHARMM.DAT with two sets of phosphoserine parameters.
\* Allowed amino acid chains with only one residue, using --assign-only 
option.
\* Updated server.py.in so that the ligand option is also recorded in 
usage.txt. 
\* Updated HE21, HE22 coordinates in GLN according to the results from 
AMBER Leap program.
\* Updated Makefile.am with Manuel Prinz's patch \(removed distclean2 and 
appended its contents to distclean-local\).
\* Updated configure.ac, pdb2pqr-opal.py; added AppService\_client.py and 
AppService\_types.py with Samir Unni's changes, which fixed earlier
problems in invoking Opal services.
\* Applied two patches from Manuel Prinz to pdb2pka/pMC\_mult.h and 
pdb2pka/ligand\_topology.py. 
\* Updated PARSE.DAT with the source of parameters. 
\* Created a contrib folder with numpy-1.1.0 package. PDB2PQR will install 
numpy by default unless any of the following conditions is met: 
a. Working version of NumPy dectected by autoconf.
b. User requests no installation with --disable-pdb2pka option.
c. User specifies external NumPy installation.  
\* Merged Samir Unni's branch. Now PDB2PQR Opal and APBS Opal services are 
available \(through --with-opal and/or --with-apbs, --with-apbs-opal 
options at configure stage\).
\* Added error handling for residue name longer than 4 characters.
\* Updated hbond.py with Mike Bradley's definitions for ANGLE\_CUTOFF and 
DIST\_CUTOFF by default.
\* Removed PyXML-0.8.4, which is not required for ZSI installation.
\* Updated propka error message for make adv-test -- propka requires a 
version of Fortran compiler.
\* Updated na.py and PATCHES.xml so that PDB2PQR handles three lettered
RNA residue names \(ADE, CYT, GUA, THY, and URA\) as well.
\* Updated NA.xml with HO2' added as an alternative name for H2'', and H5&amp;quot; 
added as an alternative name for H5''. 
\* Updated version numbers in html/ and doc/pydoc/ .
\* Updated web server. When selecting user-defined forcefield file from the 
web server, users should also provide .names file.
\* Removed http://enzyme.ucd.ie/Services/pdb2pqr/ from web server list.
\* Eliminated the need for protein when processing other types \(ligands, 
nucleic acids\).
\* Updated psize.py with Robert Konecny's patch to fix inconsistent assignment
of fine grid numbers in some \(very\) rare cases.
\* Made whitespace option available for both command line and web server 
versions.
\* Updated inputgen\_pKa.py with the latest version.

-BUG FIXES
\* Fixed a legacy bug with the web server \(web server doesn't like ligand 
files generated on Windows or old Mac OS platforms\).
\* Fixed a bug in configure.ac, so that PDB2PQR no longer checks for 
	Numpy.pth at configure stage.
\* Updated pdb2pka/substruct/Makefile.am. 
\* Fixed isBackbone bug in definitions.py.
\* Fixed a bug for Carboxylic residues in hydrogens.py.
\* Fixed a bug in routines.py, which caused hydrogens added in LEU and ILE
in eclipsed conformation rather than staggered. 
\* Fixed a bug in configure.ac, now it is OK to configure with double slashes
in the prefix path, e.g.,  --prefix=/foo/bar//another/path .
\* Fixed a bug in nucleic acid naming scheme. 
\* Fixed a bug involving MET, GLY as NTERM, CTERM with --ffout option.
\* Fixed a bug for PRO as C-terminus with PARSE forcefield. 
\* Fixed a bug for ND1 in HIS as hacceptor.
\* Fixed the --clean option bug.
\* Fixed a bug in CHARMM naming scheme.
\* Fixed a bug in test.cpp of the simple test \(which is related to recent 
modifications of 1AFS in Protein Data Bank\).

</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 17:03:35 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.netcd4d033907813b962de198a4068265e6a1d77360</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR 1.3 released</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2008/01/pdb2pqr-13-released/</link><description>Dear PDB2PQR users --

We are pleased to announce the release of PDB2PQR version 1.3.0 which contains a number of bug fixes and new features.  Major changes include:

\* The addition of test suites to verify Python is performing correctly \(e.g., &amp;quot;make test&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;make adv-test&amp;quot;\)
\* Easier and more robust configuration and installation
\* Integration with Opal for launching and querying remote jobs
\* A license change from the GNU Public License to the new BSD license \(see http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php for more information\)
\* Support for input PDB files in additional file formats generated on Windows and older MacOS systems.

More information about these modifications and a complete list of changes can be obtained from the PDB2PQR ChangeLog file provided with the source archive.  As always, the files can be downloaded from http://agave.wustl.edu/pdb2pqr/register.html

Thank you for your continuing support of PDB2PQR.

Sincerely,

The PDB2PQR Development Team</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2008 03:02:42 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net2590daaeaa2f6fda47f8926b18dc0ae3b39e4d93</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR 1.2.1</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2007/04/pdb2pqr-121/</link><description>Dear PDB2PQR users --

We are pleased to announce the release of PDB2PQR version 1.2.1 which contains a number of bug fixes and new features, including:

\* Updated documentation to include instructions for pdb2pka support, references, more pydoc documents.
\* Added new support for passing in a single ligand residue in MOL2 format via the --ligand command.  Also available from the web server \(with link to PRODRG for unsupported ligands\).
\* Added ligand examples to examples/ directory
\* Added native support for the TYL06 forcefield.  For more information on this forcefield please see
Tan C, Yang L, Luo R.  How well does Poisson-Boltzmann implicit solvent agree with explicit solvent? A quantitative analysis.  Journal of Physical Chemistry B.  110 \(37\), 18680-7, 2006.1
\* Added a new HTML output page which relays the different atom types between the AMBER and CHARMM forcefields for a generated PQR file \(thanks to the anonymous reviewers of the latest PDB2PQR paper\).
\* Numerous additions to examples directory \(see examples/index.html\) and update to User Guide.

Thank you for your continuing support of PDB2PQR.

Sincerely,

The PDB2PQR Development Team</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2007 13:21:40 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net38ac305c5a6e2b3656b988ef22f47df532fda29a</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR Public Release 1.1.2</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2006/06/pdb2pqr-public-release-112/</link><description>Hello Everyone -

I'm happy to announce the public release of PDB2PQR Version 1.1.2.
This is a bugfix release, fixing a couple of bugs that some users have
encountered over the last month.

Current users of version 1.1.1 are recommended to upgrade to the new
version at their convenience.

Thanks for your interest in PDB2PQR\!

Todd Dolinsky</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 14:49:08 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.net6066b7bbaa4afbc6b39ed14f9d0da7de16386c45</guid></item><item><title>PDB2PQR Public Release 1.1.1</title><link>http://sourceforge.net/p/pdb2pqr/news/2006/05/pdb2pqr-public-release-111/</link><description>Hello Everyone -

I'm happy to announce the release of PDB2PQR version 1.1.1.  This is
purely a bugfix release, particularly regarding two known bugs:

\* PDB2PQR is now able to recognize atoms from nucleic acids with &amp;quot;\*&amp;quot;
in their names
\* A bug that caused an unexpected SyntaxError crash during hydrogen
optimization was fixed.

Current users of version 1.1.0 are welcome to update, but only need to
do so if they have experienced one of the above issues.

Thanks\!

</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nathan Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2006 19:24:09 -0000</pubDate><guid>http://sourceforge.netd2ea85697c7e870f375b2625ebccbf7c286a3744</guid></item></channel></rss>