<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><title>Recent changes to news</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/feed.atom" rel="self"></link><id>http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/</id><updated>2014-10-30T22:19:57Z</updated><entry><title>APBS 1.4.1 released discussion</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2014/08/apbs-141-released/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-10-30T22:19:57Z</updated><published>2014-10-30T22:19:57Z</published><author><name>Jack Howarth</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/jwhowarth/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.net7917536fe0ede8cc812557dbde753851873da673</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="markdown_content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neither the sourceforge files page or the github site seems to have the apbs 1.4.1 source tarball. Only the precompiled binaries are available at the files page on the sourceforge site and only the pdb2pqr source is available on the github site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>APBS 1.4.1 released</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2014/08/apbs-141-released/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-20T03:21:37Z</updated><published>2014-08-20T03:21:37Z</published><author><name>Nathan Baker</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.net2cb8bab8cf5807e9fd095c14b8ffa3c20ca7a230</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="markdown_content"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear APBS users --&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the release of APBS 1.4.1. This was primarily a bug fix release, however, we have added a few new features we'd like to highlight:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Multigrid bug fix for volumes with large problem domains&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; We have added a preliminary implementation of geometric flow&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Finite element method support has been re-enabled&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; Migration of the APBS source tree to GitHub (https://github.com/Electrostatics/apbs-pdb2pqr) for better collaboration, issue tracking, and source code management&lt;br /&gt;
* Improved test suite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new version of APBS can be downloaded from &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/docs/downloads/#downloads." rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/docs/downloads/#downloads.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would also like to highlight our new web site, still located at: &lt;a href="http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/." rel="nofollow"&gt;http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/.&lt;/a&gt; This site is also hosted at GitHub and we hope that the new organization will make it easier for people to find the content they need. While we are still in the process of migrating some remaining content, we have added links to the previous web page when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your continuing support of APBS. As always, please use our mailing lists to send us questions or comments about our software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The APBS Development Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>APBS 1.4.0 released</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2012/08/apbs-140-released/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-01T14:20:48Z</updated><published>2012-08-01T14:20:48Z</published><author><name>Nathan Baker</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.net39b80b148ba791f35b765ace78e97057c8edfd51</id><summary type="html">Dear APBS users --

We are pleased to announce the release of APBS 1.4.0.  This version of APBS includes a massive rewrite to eliminate FORTRAN from the software code base to improve portability and facilitate planned optimization and parallelization activities.  A more detailed list of changes is provided below.

Starting with this release, we have created separate installation packages for the APBS binaries, examples, and programmer's documentation.  This change is in response to user requests and recognition of the large size of the examples and documentation directories.

As usual, APBS can be freely downloaded from http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/apbs/downloads.

Thank you for your continued support of APBS.

Sincerely,

The APBS Development Team

\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#
Please see http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/apbs/release-history for the complete change log

\# These are notes for the current version of APBS
\* Removed FORTRAN dependency from APBS
\- Direct line by line translation of all source from contrib/pmgZ
\- Functions replaced and tested incrementally to ensure code congruence
\- Created new subfolder src/pmgC for translated pmg library
\- Created new macros for 2d, 3d matrix access
&amp;gt; In src/generic/apbs/vmatrix.h
&amp;gt; Simulate native FORTRAN 2 and 3 dimensional arrays
&amp;gt; Use 1-indexed, column-major ordering
&amp;gt; Allowed direct 1-1 translation from FORTRAN to ensurre code congruence
\* Added additional debugging and output macros to src/generic/apbs/vhal.h
\- Added message, error message, assertion, warning, and abort macros
\- Macro behavior modified by the --enable-debug flag for configure
&amp;gt; Non-error messages directed to stderr in debug, io.mc otherwise
&amp;gt; All error messages are directed to stdout
&amp;gt; In debug mode, verbose location information is provided
\* Added additional flags to configure
\- --with-fetk replaces FETK\_INCLUDE, FETK\_LIBRARY environment flags
\- --with-efence enables compiling with electric fence library
\- --enable-debug eliminates compiling optimization and includes line no info
\- --enable-profiling adds profiling information and sets --enable-debug
\- --enable-verbose-debug prints lots of function specific information

\# REMOVED CODE
\* contrib/pmgZ has been removed
\* contrib/blas has been removed
\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#

</summary></entry><entry><title>New APBS Windows Installer</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2012/01/new-apbs-windows-installer/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-04T16:22:35Z</updated><published>2012-01-04T16:22:35Z</published><author><name>Nathan Baker</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.net8e2845a06686f838bee394e5f14ba630432c366c</id><summary type="html">We have released a new version of the APBS Windows Installer with the following features:

\* Ability to customize install path with correct behavior
\* Interactive command line interface when double-clicking APBS program

Please let us know if you have any questions or concerns about this new installer.

Thank you for your support of APBS.
</summary></entry><entry><title>APBS 1.3 released</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2010/10/apbs-13-released/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-27T14:56:28Z</updated><published>2010-10-27T14:56:28Z</published><author><name>Nathan Baker</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.net1d90eba3deedb27c4a1fad2cb2e6e67e5ab1624f</id><summary type="html">Dear APBS users --

We are pleased to announce the release of APBS 1.3.  This release contains several new features and bug fixes which are described in detail at http://goo.gl/l0Pt.  Among these changes are several important features which should be of broad interest to the community.

\* The primary URL for APBS Opal support has changed to leverage services provided by the National Biomedical Computation Resource \(http://nbcr.net/\).  This provides additional computational resources to users who are interested in running calculations on remote resources, as described at http://goo.gl/CHZy. 

\* APBS now supports the ability to write out atom-specific potentials using the "write atompot" keyword in the APBS input file.  This has been an often-requested feature and is described in more detail at http://goo.gl/iEAO.

\* APBS now supports the ability to read and write compressed \(GZIPped\) potential file output using the "write pot gz ..." command \(see http://goo.gl/iEAO\).

\* APBS now provides additional control over the numerical accuracy of the underlying calculations, giving users the opportunity to increase/decrease accuracy to change the speed of their calculations.

The new version of APBS can be downloaded from http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/apbs/downloads.

Thank you for your continuing support of APBS.

Sincerely,

The APBS Development Team
</summary></entry><entry><title>APBS 1.2.1 released</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2009/12/apbs-121-released/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-03T02:31:01Z</updated><published>2009-12-03T02:31:01Z</published><author><name>Nathan Baker</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.net283079ea9318d7ee451f91e7767d944cf2f7c813</id><summary type="html">Dear APBS Users --

APBS 1.2.1 has been released.  This is a bugfix release specifically aimed at addressing a problem with certain nonlinear Poisson-Boltzmann calculations.  In particular, several users noticed that Poisson-Boltzmann calculations which focused into a low dielectric region would occasionally generate very large \(~1E25 kJ/mol\) energies.  This was due to a bug that caused instability in the nonlinear Poisson-Boltzmann solver.  This bug has been fixed in this release.

The full list of changes is:
	• Added in warning into focusFillBound if there is a large value detected in setting the boundary conditions during a focusing calculation
	• Added in a check and abort in Vpmg\_qmEnergy if chopped values are detected. This occurs under certain conditions for NPBE calculations where focusing cuts into a low-dielectric regions.
	• Fixed a bug in Vpmg\_MolIon that causes npbe based calculations to return very large energies.  This occurs under certain conditions for NPBE calculations where focusing cuts into a low-dielectric regions.

More information about APBS as well as download links can be obtained from http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/.

We apologize for this bug and thank you for your continued support of APBS.

Sincerely,

The APBS Development Team</summary></entry><entry><title>APBS 1.2.0 released</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2009/10/apbs-120-released/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-22T15:17:27Z</updated><published>2009-10-22T15:17:27Z</published><author><name>Nathan Baker</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.net5e0a90b51b3724a140618c9bf1fb4fcc7479113f</id><summary type="html">Hi All --

We are pleased to announce the latest release of APBS, version 1.2.0, available for download from http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/apbs/downloads.  This version features a number of changes which are summarized online \(http://tinyurl.com/apbs-1-2-0\).  Highlights include:

\* Limited OpenMP support to parallelize computationally-intensive portions of APBS
\* Improved Opal support
\* Bug fixes

This release also marks the introduction of our new website for APBS at http://www.poissonboltzmann.org/apbs.

Please let us know if you have any questions or concerns about APBS and thank you for your continued support of APBS.

Sincerely,

The APBS Development Team</summary></entry><entry><title>APBS 1.1.0</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2009/03/apbs-110/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-03-09T14:50:08Z</updated><published>2009-03-09T14:50:08Z</published><author><name>Nathan Baker</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.nete257233159e58d5a5cd56c037e53a8cc41cdceb7</id><summary type="html">We are pleased to announce the release of APBS 1.1.0.  This version of the software contains a number of new features including an Opal-based web services client to allow users to run calculations on remote computers and a new documentation site \(http://apbs.wustl.edu/\) with an improved user guide and tutorials.  As usual, APBS can be downloaded from http://apbs.sourceforge.net/ and help can be obtained from the APBS-users mailing list.</summary></entry><entry><title>APBS 1.0.0</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2008/04/apbs-100/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-04-21T17:39:54Z</updated><published>2008-04-21T17:39:54Z</published><author><name>Nathan Baker</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.net1c571135d210d62b64b890b56fc81bb12b115c7a</id><summary type="html">We are very pleased to announce the availability of APBS 1.0.0, a major update of APBS which contains a few bug fixes and several new features.  A full change log for this release is attached below. 

As usual, the latest version of APBS can be downloaded from http://apbs.sourceforge.net/ which also contains links to the software documentation and tutorials.

Thank you for your continuing interest in APBS.

Sincerely,

The APBS Development Team

\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#
VERSION 1.0.0
April 2008
\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#
\- NEW FEATURES
\* Changed license to New BSD style open source license \(see http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php\) for more information
\* Added in a feature limited version of PMG \(Aqua\) that reduces the memory footprint of an APBS run by 2-fold
\* Modified several routines to boost the speed of APBS calculations by approximately 10% when combined with the low memory version of APBS
\* Simplified parameter input for ION and SMPBE keywords \(key-value pairs\) 
\* Examples and documentation for size-modified PBE code \(Vincent Chu et al\)
\* Added in &amp;quot;fast&amp;quot; compile-time option that uses optimized parameters for multigrid calculations
\* mg-dummy calculations can be run with any number \(n&amp;gt;3\) of grid points
\* Updated PMG license to LGPL
\* Added per-atom SASA information output from APOLAR calculations
\* Added per-atom verbosity to APOLAR calculation outputs
\* Ability to read-in MCSF-format finite element meshes \(e.g., as produced by Holst group GAMER soft
ware\)
\* Updated installation instructions in user guide
\- BUG FIXES
\* Updated tools/python/apbslib\* for new NOsh functionality
\* Clarified ELEC/DIME and ELEC/PDIME documentation
\* Added more transparent warnings/error messages about path lengths which exceed the 80-character limit
\* Fixed small typo in user guide in installation instructions
\* Fixed memory leaks throughout the APBS code
\* Fixed NOsh\_parseREAD errors for input files with \r line feeds.
\* Fixed a variable setting error in the test examples
\* Fixed a bug where memory usage is reported incorrectly for large allocations on 64-bit systems
\* Added DTRSV to APBS-supplied BLAS to satisfy FEtk SuperLU dependency

</summary></entry><entry><title>APBS 0.5.1</title><link href="http://sourceforge.net/p/apbs/news/2007/07/apbs-051/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-07-17T18:17:58Z</updated><published>2007-07-17T18:17:58Z</published><author><name>Nathan Baker</name><uri>http://sourceforge.net/u/sobolevnrm/</uri></author><id>http://sourceforge.net257ba8e059032517341c70c910e375339710d0dd</id><summary type="html">We are pleased to announce the release of APBS 0.5.1, a minor update which fixes problems where 'bcfl sdh' behaved as 'bcfl zero' for net neutral proteins and includes a few new features.  A full change log for this release is attached below and we apologize for any problems this bug may have caused.

As usual, the latest version of APBS can be downloaded from http://apbs.sourceforge.net/ which also contains links to the software documentation and tutorials.

Thank you for your continued interest in APBS.

Sincerely,

The APBS Development Team

\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#
VERSION 0.5.1
July 2007
\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#
\- NEW FEATURES
\* Replaced APOLAR-&amp;gt;glen and APOLAR-&amp;gt;dime keywords with APOLAR-&amp;gt;grid
\* Deprecated mergedx. Added mergedx2
\- mergedx2 takes the bounding box that a user wishes to calculate a map for, as well as a resolution of the output map. An output map meeting those specifications is calculated and store.
\* Added pKa tutorial
\* Added warning about strange grid settings \(MGparm\)
\* Fixed a bug in vpmg.c that occured when a user supplied a dielectric map with the ionic strength set to zero, causing the map to not be used.
\* Removed deprecated \(as of 0.5.0\) tools/manip/acc in lieu of new APOLAR APBS features
\* Added enumerations for return codes, new PBE solver \(SMPBE\) and linear/ nonlinear types
\* Added in code for Size-Modified PBE \(SMPBE\)
\- BUG FIXES
\* Fixed buffer over-run problem
\* Fixed case inconsistency with inputgen.py and psize.py scripts which caused problems with some versions of Python
\* Fixed bug wherein 'bcfl sdh' behaved essentially like 'bcfl zero'.  Now we have the correct behavior:  'bcfl sdh' behaves like 'bcfl mdh' thanks to the multipole code added by Mike Schnieders.  Interestingly, this bug didn't have a major on the large-molecule test cases/examples provided by APBS but did affect the small molecule solvation energies.  Thanks to Bradley Scott Perrin for reporting this bug.
\* Added support for chain IDs in noinput.py
\* Fixed bug in noinput.py where REMARK lines would cause the script to fail.
\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#\#
</summary></entry></feed>